Earlier in this lesson,
在这节课的前面阶段
you were introduced to an iterative method for
我们介绍了计算策略
determining the value function corresponding to a policy.
对应的值函数的迭代方法
In this video, we'll discuss the algorithm in more detail.
在本视频中 我们将详细讲解该算法
The algorithm is called iterative policy evaluation,
该算法称为迭代策略评估
and it assumes that the agent already has
假设智能体已经完全了解
full and perfect knowledge of the MDP that characterizes the environment.
关于环境的 MDP
Remember that this algorithm was motivated by
注意 该算法的依据是
the Bellman expectation equation for the state-value function.
状态值函数的贝尔曼预期方程
And this equation is really a system of equations
该方程本质上是个方程组
since we have one equation for each environment state.
因为每个环境状态都有一个方程
Each equation relates the value of a state to the values of its successor states.
每个方程将状态值与后续状态的值关联起来
Theoretically, since we have a system of equations
理论上来说 如果有一个方程组
with one equation for each unknown quantity,
每个未知元素都有一个方程
we could solve this system.
那么可以求解该方程组
But there's an easier way where instead of solving the system exactly,
但是还有一种更简单的方法 我们不用完全求解该方程组
we'll construct an iterative algorithm where each step gets us
而是构建一个迭代算法
closer and closer to solving this system of equations.
每一步都使我们越来越接近于求解该方程组
Specifically, our iterative algorithm will adapt this Bellman equation,
具体而言 我们的迭代算法将调整该贝尔曼方程
so it can be used as an update rule.
因此可以当做更新规则
Here, the capital V denotes the current guess for the policy's value function.
大写的 V 表示对策略的值函数的当前猜测
Note that I've only changed two things about
注意 我只更改了贝尔曼方程的两个部分
the Bellman equation which I've underlined in yellow here.
我用黄色标出来了
So the algorithm begins with an initial guess for the value function of the policy.
该算法先对策略的值函数进行初始猜测
What's typically done is to set the initial guess for each state to zero.
通常是将每个状态的初始猜测设为 0
Okay, and so there's no way that's actually
因此不可能这就是真正的值函数
the true value function but we just need to start somewhere.
但是我们只是进行一个初始猜测
Then we'll loop over the states and use
然后我们将循环访问每个状态
the update rule to improve our guess for the state-value function.
并使用更新规则改善对状态值函数的猜测
And what's nice is that as long as a few technical conditions are satisfied,
真正妙的是只要满足几个技术性条件
this algorithm is guaranteed to converge to the value function for the policy.
这个算法就能保证会向该策略的值函数收敛
Now we can only attain true convergence and the limit of
要获得真正的收敛效果
running this algorithm an infinite number of times,
就必须运行该算法无限次
and that's not feasible in practice.
这在现实中是不可行的
So, we'll have to stop short of true convergence.
因此我们将在刚要真正收敛之前停止
And the question is, how can we tell when we've gotten close enough?
问题是 如何判断已经很接近了？
Well in practice, when you implement the algorithm,
在现实中 当你实现该算法时
you'll notice that the first few times the update step is applied,
你将发现前几次应用更新规则时
there are big changes to the value function.
值函数的变化非常大
But then eventually, at a later time point,
但是在后续阶段
you'll notice that updates are hardly noticeable.
你将发现几乎没有变化
And once we get to that point where applying
当我们应用更新规则后
the update rule doesn't change the estimate of the value function much,
值函数的估值变化不大
that's a strong indication that our algorithm has gotten
这种情况就强烈表示
reasonably close to converging to the true value function.
我们的算法已经非常收敛于真正的值函数
And so inspired by this fact,
因此
we can design a stopping criterion that terminates
我们可以设计一个停止条件
the algorithm whenever we've done a complete pass over all the states,
当我们完整地遍历了所有状态
and none of the values has changed much.
所有值都没有什么变化时 则停止该算法
To do this, we'll amend the pseudo code where the first step is for
为此 我们将修改伪代码
you to set a very small positive number theta.
第一步是需要你来设置一个非常小的正 θ
Next, ask before you initialize the first guess for the value function to be all zeroes.
然后和之前一样 将值函数的初始猜测全设为 0
Then you enter the iterative loop where each step you apply
然后进行迭代循环
the Bellman update and check to see how
在每一步应用贝尔曼更新规则
much the values for each of the states has changed.
检查每个状态的值变化幅度
If the maximum change over all states is
如果所有状态的最大变化
less than that small number of theta that you set,
小于所设置的小数字 θ
then you stop the algorithm and say that
则停止该算法
your estimate for the value function is good enough.
并表示值函数的估值已经很不错
And that's it. But now if that updates step feels suspicious to you, I don't blame you.
就这样 如果你不太熟悉这个更新步骤 也不用担心
And your instincts to want to prove are correct.
你的直觉是想证明这一步 这很正常
It's not at all intuitive that this algorithm should work the way it does.
这个算法并不是那么的直观
But here's the main idea behind what that update step is doing.
下面说说更新步骤的原理
Remember that we loop over states and apply the update to one state at a time.
我们循环访问状态 并且每次向一个状态应用更新规则
And from each state,
然后对于每个状态
the agent could choose any of a number of
智能体都可以选择任何一个潜在的动作
possible actions that bring it to any of a number of potential next states.
并进入任何一个潜在后续状态
And the Bellman equation helps us relate the value of
贝尔曼方程可以帮助我们将此父状态的值
this parent state to the values of all of its possible successor states.
与所有潜在后续状态的值相关联
Now what we do is, look at the estimated value function for the parent state,
现在我们查看父状态的估算值函数
along with the values of the successor states.
以及后续状态的值
And if we plug in those values to the Bellman equation,
如果将这些值代入贝尔曼方程
and it's not satisfied,
会发现方程不满足
what we'll do is, we'll change the value of
我们将更改父状态的值
the parent state so that the Bellman equation is satisfied.
以便满足贝尔曼方程
Then, we'll do the same for the second state and so on.
然后对第二个状态执行相同的流程 以此类推
And what's important to note is that if at some point,
需要注意的是
we go to apply this update rule and there's no change in
如果在某个时刻应用该更新规则时
any of the values of any of the states, then that means,
任何状态的任何值都没有变化
we have a value function that perfectly satisfies the Bellman equation,
则表明 我们获得了完全满足贝尔曼方程的值函数
and the only value function that does that is the true value function of the policy.
唯一满足这一条件的值函数是真正的策略值函数
We won't go deeper into this in the video, but as always,
在本视频中我们将不再赘述
if you'd like to discuss further,
但是和往常一样 如果你想深入了解
you're encouraged to ask questions in the office hours or post in the slack channels.
建议你在问答时间内提出问题或将问题发布到相关 slack 频道上
But now, it's time for you to implement this algorithm yourself.
现在该你自己来实现该算法了